Finding Aid for Muschenheim, William. Architectural drawings and papers. 1925-1990
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Project Files
  - Job 113, William J. Murphy
    - William J. Murphy, residence (Remensburg, N.Y.)
      - Drawings, #.02637-.02779 1941-1950, 143 sheets: various media; or smaller 95.5 x 119.4 cm.; 37-5/8 x 47 inches
        - Details and elevations [of] pantry and porch [for] N.W. wing [with notes and measurements]: Drawing 9 / [drawn by J.L.] 03/22/1949 revised, 5/3/1949, NYDA.1986.004.02705
        - Elevations and details, [plan and ceiling plan of the] play rm.-N.W. wing [with notes and measurements]: Drawing 10 3/22/1949, NYDA.1986.004.02706
        - Elevations and details, [plan and ceiling plan of the] play rm.-N.W. wing [with notes and measurements]: Drawing 10 3/22/1949 Blueprint on paper., NYDA.1986.004.02707
          (Copied from 1986.004.02705.)
        - Plan of attic in center building [with notes and measurements]: Drawing 11 4/4/1949, NYDA.1986.004.02708
        - Study "G", new partitions in old attic (center building): [for Drawing 11], NYDA.1986.004.02709
        - Study "G", new partitions in old attic (center building): [for Drawing 11]., NYDA.1986.004.02710
        - Details at entrance [showing sections, plans and elevations, with notes and measurements, of the] S.E. wing: Drawing 12 / [drawn by J.L.] 04/05/1949, revised 10/6/1949, NYDA.1986.004.02711
        - [Floor plan, reflected ceiling plan,] interior elevations and details-S.E. wing [with notes and measurements]: Drawing 13 / [drawn by J.L.] 5/6/1949, NYDA.1986.004.02712
        - Miscellaneous details [including elevation of garage passage and details of the sunshade over the south facade of the enclosed porch; chimney construction; and the N.W. corner of the enclosed porch; with notes and measurements]: Drawing 14 / [drawn by J.L.] 5/6/1949, NYDA.1986.004.02713
        - Ext. door to canvas deck W. F.S. detail sects. [and an elevation showing the door w. adj. window, with notes and measurements]: Drawing 15 5/11/1949, NYDA.1986.004.02714
        - Details, [elevations] and sects.-ext. dr. to deck, yd. fences, trellis, etc.-N.W. wing [with notes and measurements]: Drawing 15A / [drawn by J.L.] 5/18/1949, NYDA.1986.004.02715
        - Details of sash under w/7 [showing a section and an ext. elevation at kitchen entry, with notes and measurements]: Drawing 15-B 5/24/1949, NYDA.1986.004.02716
        - Details of sash under w/7 [showing a section and an ext. elevation at kitchen entry, with notes and measurements]: Drawing 15-B 5/24/1949, NYDA.1986.004.02717
        - Alterations to doors [showing elevations and sections, with notes and measurements]: Drawing 1b 6/1/1949, NYDA.1986.004.02718
        - Misc. details at entry [showing plans, elevation and sections for ext. sliding gates under pantry, folding ironing table and vimlite panel, with notes and measurements]: Drawing 17 / [drawn by J.L.] 6/23/1949, NYDA.1986.004.02719
        - Misc. details at entry [showing plans, elevations and section for ext. sliding gates under pantry, folding ironing table and vimlite panel, with notes and measurements]: Drawing 17 / [drawn by J.L.] 06/23/1949 revised, July 7, 1949, NYDA.1986.004.02720
        - Wiring diag. of intercommunicating system [with notes]: Drawing 18 7/14/1949, NYDA.1986.004.02721
        - Window and terrace revisions-S.E. [showing ext. and int. elevations, a foundation plan, and detail sections, with notes and measurements and a window schedule]: Drawing 19 / [drawn by J.L.] 09/29/1949 revised, 10/18/1949, NYDA.1986.004.02722
        - Revised d't'ls of cabinette, shop and passage ceil. [showing a floor plan, reflected ceiling plan, east ext. elevation, and detail sections, with notes and measurements]: Drawing 20 10/28/1949 revised, 11/28/1949, NYDA.1986.004.02723
        - F.S. d't'ls of sash [with notes and measurements]: Drawing 21, 11/4/49, revised 11/9/49 11/15/1949, NYDA.1986.004.02724
        - F.S. d't'ls of sash (continued) [and plan of plant shelf in passage, with notes and measurements]: Drawing 22 11/18/1949, NYDA.1986.004.02725
        - Revised elec. diagram and miscellaneous details [showing a plan, int. elevs. of master's bedroom, and details sections, with notes and measurements]: Drawing 23 / [drawn by S.S.], 12/1/49, revised 12/8/49 12/15/1949, NYDA.1986.004.02726
        - Ventilation, cabinet, etc. in Master's bath [showing north, south and west int. elevs.; ext. elev. at w. end of passage; and detail sections, with notes and measurements]: Drawing 24, 12/8/1949, NYDA.1986.004.02727
        - Revised d't'ls at entry [showing a floor plan, reflected ceiling plan, elevation of wardrobe wall in enclosed porch, and end elevation of cabinet, with notes and measurements]: Drawing 25 12/15/1949, NYDA.1986.004.02728
        - Valence and blinds in enclosed porch [showing a south and east elev., with notes and measurements]: Drawing 25 1/12/1950, NYDA.1986.004.02729
        - Valence and blinds in enclosed porch [showing a south and east elev., with notes and measurements]: Drawing 25 1/12/1950 Blueprint with pastel on paper, NYDA.1986.004.02730
        - Lay-out of planting [showing a site plan, with notes and measurements]: Drawing 26 3/21/1950, NYDA.1986.004.02731
        - Lay-out of planting [showing a site plan, with notes and measurements]: Drawing 26 3/21/1950 Blueprint with pastel on paper. Verso shows notes, NYDA.1986.004.02732
        - Lay-out of planting [with notes and measurements]: Drawing 26-A 4/5/1950, NYDA.1986.004.02733
        - Lay-out of planting [with notes and measurements]: Drawing 26-A, 4/5/50, revised 04/12/1950, 4/18/1950, NYDA.1986.004.02734
        - Plan and elevations of plant box [with notes and measurements]: Drawing 27 4/10/1950, NYDA.1986.004.02735
        - [Site plan with first floor plan]., NYDA.1986.004.02736; Ink and plastic self-adhesive film dot screen on tracing paper.
        - [Site plan with first floor plan], 1950., NYDA.1986.004.02737
          (Stat on paper. A reduction of 1986.004.02736. Verso showing notes.)
        - [Exterior elevation and partial plan, with notes and measurements] / [drawn by M.A.L.] 11/14/1941, NYDA.1986.004.02738
        - Heating [showing cellar, first and second floor plans, as well as an oblique view of the steam boiler, with notes and measurements] / [drawn by] M.A.L. January 6, 1942, NYDA.1986.004.02739
        - Study of sunshade-S. end of S.E. porch [with notes and measurements], NYDA.1986.004.02740
        - [Study for] master's bed room and measurements], NYDA.1986.004.02741
        - [Study for] master's bath room [windows showing an elevation with notes and measurements], NYDA.1986.004.02742
        - [Study for a flower pot(?) showing a section with notes and measurements], NYDA.1987.004.02743
        - [Study of windows(?) showing a partial elevation with notes], N YDA.1986.004.02744
        - [Unidentified study with measurements], NYDA.1986.004.02745
        - [Sketch of] ext. sills at drs. [showing an elevation with notes and measurements]., NYDA.1986.004.02746
        - [Sketch of an unidentified plan(?)], NYDA.1986.004.02747
        - [Sketch of an ash can, with measurements], NYDA.1986.004.02748
        - [Unidentified sketch with notes and measurements], NYDA.1986.004.02749
        - [Sketch of] playroom and windows on 2nd fl. [showing a plan with notes and measurements], NYDA.1986.004.02750
        - [Sketch of] kitchen porch [showing a plan with measurements], NYDA.1986.004.02751
        - [Sketch of] east attic [showing a floor plan with notes and measurements], NYDA.1986.004.02752
        - [Sketch of] north elev. [with notes and measurements], NYDA.1986.004.02753
        - [Sketch of] E. elev. of N.W. wing [with notes and measurements], NYDA.1986.004.02754
        - [Sketch of] south elev. [with measurements], NYDA.1986.004.02755
        - [Sketch of] kitchen [showing a plan with notes and measurements], NYDA.1986.004.02756
        - [Sketch of a block plan with measurements], NYDA.1986.004.02757
        - [Sketch of] east elevation [with measurements], NYDA.1986.004.02758
        - [Sketch of] general plan [with measurements], NYDA.1986.004.02759
        - [Sketch of] master's bath [showing elevations with notes and measurements], NYDA.1986.004.02760
        - [Sketch of] master's bedroom [showing a plan with notes and measurements], NYDA.1986.004.02761
        - [Sketch of an unidentified plan with measurements], NYDA.1986.004.02762
        - [Sketch of an unidentified foundation(?) plan with measurements], NYDA.1986.004.02763
        - [Sketch of a partial block plan with measurements], NYDA.1986.004.02764
        - [Sketch of] south terrace level [showing a detail section with notes and measurements], NYDA.1986.004.02765
        - [Sketches of kitchen showing a partial plan, an elevation and an axonometric sketch of a veg. bin with notes and measurements], NYDA.1986.004.02766
        - [Sketch of] west elev. [showing an exterior view with notes and measurements], NYDA.1986.004.02767
        - [Ceiling light fixture showing a section with notes] / Ledlin Light Designers, Inc, NYDA.1986.004.02768
        - [Light fixture showing a F.S. section with notes and measurements] / Ledlin Light Designers, Inc, NYDA.1986.004.02769
        - [Light fixtures showing 3 F.S. sections with notes and measurements]: Drawing no. 186 / Ledlin Light Designers, Inc.; dwn. by H.G., 4/14/1949, NYDA.1986.004.02770
          (Verso notes fixture is for N.W. wing.)
        - Murphy Cabranette E48-87E recessed type [showing a plan, section, elevation and roughing diagram with notes and measurements] / [Murphy Door Bed Company], 12/5/1947, NYDA.1986.004.02771
        - Murphy cabranette E48-87S standard type [showing a plan, section, elevation and a roughing diagram with notes and measurements] / [Murphy Door Bed Company] 9/15/1947, NYDA.1986.004.02772
        - [Duplicate copy of 1986.004.02772], NYDA.1986.004.02773
        - Raised oper. bar [where] all vents operate [showing F.S. sections, with notes and measurements]: Drawing no. 139 Rev. / Gate City Sash & Door Co.; [dwn by] G.R.H. 8/13/1947, NYDA.1986.004.02774
        - Type 'D' awning window for frame wall [showing a partial elevation and detail sections, with notes and measurements]: Drawing No. 3760 Rev. / Gate City Sash & Door Co.; [dwn. by] G.R.H., 11/14/1946, NYDA.1986.004.02775
        - Std. Jalousie door detail, Type 'E' [showing sections and elevation, with notes, a table, and measurements]: Drawing 3022 Rev. / Gate City Sash & Door Co.; [dwn. by] G.R.H., 12-24-46, NYDA.1986.004.02776
        - [Ventilighter blind showing a plan, elevation, and detail sections with notes and measurements]: Job no. 1089 order #22 / Simon Ventilighter Co. Inc.; drawn by H.K., 1/24/1950, NYDA.1986.004.02777
        - [Ventilighter blind showing a plan, elevation, and detail sections with notes and measurements]: Job no. 1089 order #22 / Simon Ventilighter Co. Inc.; drawn by H.K., 01/24/1950 revised, 1/31/1950, NYDA.1986.004.02778
        - Automatic outlet or inlet louvers 3" thick w/ blades tied [with notes and measurements]: Drawing No. 525-1-b / The Airolite Company; by H.G.R.; redrawn by R.W. Graham, 6/4/46, [rev.] 10/9/1948, NYDA.1986.004.02779
        - Rendering undated, watercolor on blueline mounted on board (Map-case B1)
      - Papers
        - Shop Drawings (Box A18, Folder 113-1)
          (1 printed drawing(?) of enameled sink.)
        - Studies (Box A18, Folder 113-9)
          (3 sheets, 3 pages of computations.)
        - drawings, (4 sheets, packet of legal paper) (Box A18, Folder 113-10)
          (1 small, torn page of notes.)
        - prints, B&W photographs showing interior of residence (Box A18, Folder 113-11)
          (Folder 18)
          (2 items, 1 color print of drawing showing exterior of residence.)
        - archival, Correspondence, corresponds to Folder 1, drawings: (Box A18, Folder 113-12)
          (2 pieces of correspondence from William J. Murphy, and 6 items relating to bathroom fixtures and Jalousies doors.)
        - archival, Specifications (Box A18, Folder 113-13)
          (specifications, hardware schedule.)
        - archival, Superintendent Reports (Box A18, Folder 113-14)
          (specifications, superintendence reports.)
        - archival, Surveys corresponds with Folder 10 of drawings (Box A18, Folder 113-15)
          (pamphlets relating to product information)
        - Accounts and Memos (Box A18, Folder 113-16)
          (bills, notes, memos, pamphlets, samples. Worked with: Asbestos Construction Company, Inc., Ledlin Light Designers, Inc., Simon Ventilighter Co., Inc., Gotham Lighting Corporation, The Aeroshade Company, Knoll Associates, Ostrander & Eshleman Inc., Reynolds Metals Company, Knit-Wood Shade & Screen Co., and others.)
        - Estimates and Legal (Box A18, Folder 113-17)
          (1 agreement, and various material related to estimates.)
        - Estimates and Legal (Box A18, Folder 113-18)
          (3 drawings of lights.)
        - Correspondence (Box A18, Folder 113-19)
          (Corresponded with: William J. Murphy, Acorn Houses, Inc., and others.)
        - Accounts (Box A18, Folder 113-20)
          (statements, orders, certificates, accounts charts.)
        - archival, 1 sheet found with drawings Folder 8 (Box A18, Folder 113-21)
          (1 empty envelope)
        - archival, 1 sheet found with drawings (Box A18, Folder 113-220)
          (1 Knoll Associates advertisement for a chair.)
      - Presentation Boards
        - Addition to House, Remsenburg, L.I. 1949 (Map-case B7)
      - Photographs
  - Job 114, Mrs. H. Burnet
    - [Hedwig Wilkes Burnet Apartment 156 East 79th Street New York N Y Alterations]
      - Drawings, #.02780-.02795 December 1948-April 1949, 14 sheets: various media; or smaller 53.5 x 83.7 cm.; 21-1/8 x 33 inches
        (This set consists of 6 pencil on tracing paper, 6 pencil on paper, and 2 pencil with pastel on paper. Mrs. H. Burnet was also cited as Mrs. Wilkes Burnet and Mrs. Hedwig Burnet in the archives.)
        - Storage closet and mantel [showing an interior elevation, plan, oblique view and detail sections, with notes and measurements]: Drawing 1, 12/3/48., NYDA.1986.004.02780
        - Plan and elevations of N.W. bed room [with notes and measurements]: Drawing 2 / [dwn. by T.C.], 12/10/48., NYDA.1986.004.02781
        - Plan and elevation of desks [and a F.S.D. section, with notes and measurements]: Drawing 3, 1/7/49., NYDA.1986.004.02782
        - Plans and elevs. of fold-away table [with notes and measurements]: Drawing 4, 2/4/49., NYDA.1986.004.02783
        - Plan, elev. and sect. of bench [with notes and measurements]: Drawing 5, 4/15/49., NYDA.1986.004.02784
        - . [Study of N.W. bedroom showing a plan and detail sections with notes and measurements]., NYDA.1986.004.02785 R
        - [Study of living rm. showing a partial plan and partial elevation with notes and measurements]., NYDA.1986.004.02785 V
        - [Unidentified study 1 showing a plan(?) with measurements]., NYDA.1986.004.02786
        - [Unidentified study 2 showing a plan(?) with measurements]., NYDA.1986.004.02787
        - [Unidentified study 3 showing a plan(?) with measurements]., NYDA.1986.004.02788
        - [Unidentified study 4 showing details with measurements]., NYDA.1986.004.02789
        - [Study of a mantel showing an oblique view with measurements]., NYDA.1986.004.02790
        - [Study of a desk showing an isometric view with measurements]., NYDA.1986.004.02791
        - [Study of the foyer showing elevations with notes and measurements]. Verso is a calendar page noted., NYDA.1986.004.02792
        - [Unidentified study with notes and measurements]., NYDA.1986.004.02793
      - Papers
        - archival, Surveys and Corresp. (Box A18, Folder 114-2)
          (carpet and fabric samples, notes, correspondence, statements, certificates, orders, accounts charts, and other accounts material. Worked with: Gustave Dickwisch (carpentry), Raustein & Festis (painting), Joseph Aronson Inc. (furniture design), Waldron Associates (designers & distributors of furniture), Frank Pulick Glass, Tudoran Trade Shop, Charles Hyman (electrical contractor), and others.)
  - Job 115, City and Country School
    - City and Country School (New York, NY)
      - Drawings, #.02794-.02795 February 9, 1949, 2 sheets: various media; or smaller 64 x 55.6 cm.; 25-1/4 x 21-7/8 inches
        This set consists of 1 pencil on tracing paper and 1 blueprint on paper.
        - Preliminary plan, [exterior] elevation and section [with notes and measurements]: Drawing A / [dwn. by J.L.] 2/9/1949, NYDA.1986.004.02794
        - Preliminary plan, [exterior] elevation and section [with notes and measurements]: Drawing A / [dwn. by J.L.], 2/9/1949, NYDA.1986.004.02795; Blueprint on paper.
      - Papers
        - archival, Accounts, Corresp., and Surveys (Box A18, Folder 115-2)
          (notes, correspondence, 4 drawings, 1 statement, 1 accounts chart.)
  - Job 116, W.A. Cooper
    - Dr. W.A. Cooper 1949
      - Papers
        - archival, Corresp., Surveys, and Accounts (Box A18, Folder 116-1)
  - Job 117, Joseph Aronson
    - Joseph Aronson 1949
      - Papers
        - Accounts (Box A18, Folder 117-1)
  - Job 118, Immo Gulden
    - Paul Immo Gulden apartment, 155 East 49th Street, NYC
      - Drawings, #.02796-.02808, 9 sheets: various media; or smaller 65 x 84 cm.; 25-5/8 x 33-1/8 inches
        This set consists of 4 pencil on tracing paper, 1 blueprint with pastel on paper, 3 blackline prints with pastel on paper, and 1 blackline print with pastel and ink on paper.
        - Plan, elevations and details [of dinette, living rm. and bed rm., with notes and measurements]: Drawing 1 04/21/1949 rev., 4/28/1949, NYDA.1986.004.02796
        - Plan, elevations and details [of dinette, living rm. and bed rm., with notes and measurements]: Drawing 1 04/21/1949 rev., 4/18/1949, NYDA.1986.004.02797; Blackline print with pastel and ink.
        - D'l's of corner table and standing lamp w. glass shelf [showing plans elevations and sections, with notes and measurements]: Drawing 2 10/25/1949, NYDA.1986.004.02798
        - D't'ls of upholstered couch [showing front and side elevations, with notes and measurements]: Drawing 3 10/25/1949, NYDA.1986.004.02799
        - D't'ls of upholstered couch [showing front and side elevations, with notes and measurements]: Drawing 3 10/25/1949 Blueprint with pastel on paper, NYDA.1986.004.02800
        - [Study of couch and corner table showing axonometric views, plans and an elevation], NYDA.1986.004.02801
        - [Ceiling light fixture showing a section with notes and measurements] / Ledlin Light Designers, Inc, NYDA.1986.004.02802
        - [Hanging ceiling light fixture showing a section with notes and measurements] / Ledlin Light Designers, Inc, NYDA.1986.004.02803
        - [Wall light fixture showing a section with notes and measurements] / Ledlin Light Designers, Inc, NYDA.1986.004.02804
      - Papers
        - archival, Surveys and Corresp. (Box A18, Folder 118-2)
          (correspondence, estimates, samples of various materials, order contract, 4 pages of drawings)
        - archival, Accounts (Box A18, Folder 118-3)
          (statements, accounts charts, memos, orders, certificates, and other accounts related material. Worked with: Raustin & Festis (painting), Alfred B. Howes (upholstered furniture), Joseph Aronson Inc. (furniture), Finsven (furniture, fabric), Ledlin Lighting, Inc., Arundell Clarke, F. Schumacher & Co. (fabrics), Gustave Dickwisch (carpentry), and others.)
  - Job 119, Dr. Carl Muschenheim
    - Dr. Carl Muschenheim 215 East 72nd St. NYC
      - Drawings, #.02805-.02808 June-October, 1949
        This set consists of 2 pencil on tracing paper, 1 pencil with pastel on tracing paper, and 1 blackline print with pastel and ink on paper.
        - Plan and room elevations [showing interior views of the den, living rm., foyer, and dining rm.; and detail sections, with notes and measurements]: Drawing 1 / [dwn. by W.M. and J.L.] 6/28/1949, NYDA.1986.004.02805
        - Plan and room elevations [showing interior views of the den, living rm., foyer, and dining rm.; and detail sections, with notes and measurements]: Drawing 1 / [dwn. by W.M. and J.L.] 06/28/1949 revised, 7/7/1949 Blackline print with pastel and ink on paper, NYDA.1986.004.02806
        - Details of side-board [showing an elevation, plan, and detail sections, with notes and measurements]: Drawing 2 6/28/1949, NYDA.1986.004.02807
        - Details of wood box [showing an isometric view and detail sections, with notes and measurements]: Drawing 3 10/17/1949, NYDA.1986.004.02808
      - Papers
        - archival, Surveys and Memos (Box A19, Folder 120-5)
          (samples, notes, memos.)
        - archival, Estimates, Accounts, and Correspondence (Box A19, Folder 120-6)
          (certificates, statements, orders, invoices, account charts, notes, samples. Worked with: Knoll Associates, Hale's Bedding, Loosen & Brautigam (cabinet makers), Breinig Brothers, Inc. (paints, varnishes), Murray Hill Woodworking Corp., Jensen-Lewis Company (awnings, canopies), J.W. Fiske Iron Works, and others.)
  - Job 120, William J. Murphy
    - William J. Murphy apartment, 993 Fifth Ave., NYC
      - Drawings, .02809-.02856, 48 sheets: various media; or smaller 106 x 94.2 cm.; 41-3/4 x 37-1/8 inches
        Drawings from this project include: Muschenheim's numbered drawings and studies (1986.004.02809-.02836), Joseph J. Breitman's alteration (1986.004.02837), and contractors' drawings (1986.004.02838-.02847). This set consists of 11 pencil on tracing paper, 1 pencil with pastel on tracing paper, 5 pencil on paper, 6 pencil with pastel on paper, 13 blueprints with pastel on paper, 3 blackline prints on paper, and 9 blackline prints with pastel on paper.
        - Preliminary plan, elevations and details [with notes and measurements]: Drawing 1 / [drawn by J.T.A.L.] 07/20/1949 revised, 8/2/1949, NYDA.1986.004.02809
        - [Duplicate of 1986.004.02809], NYDA.1986.004.02810
        - Preliminary plan, elevations and details [with notes and measurements]: Drawing 1 / [drawn by J.T.A.L.] 07/20/1949 revised, 8/16/1949, NYDA.1986.004.02811
        - Closet, bookcases and fireplace details [showing interior elevations, plans, and sections, with notes and measurements]: Drawing 2 / [drawn by J.T.A.L.], August 9, 1949 to revised August 16, 1949, NYDA.1986.004.02812
        - Plans and sections of valances [for living rm., library and master bed rm., showing sections, and plans with notes and measurements]: Drawing 3 / [drawn by J.T.A.L.], August 17, 1949, NYDA.1986.004.02813
        - [Second floor :] miscellaneous details [of sliding plexiglass panel in the dressing rm., closet trays and shelves in the master bed rm., shelf doors in the play rm., and lighting and curtain tracks in the dining rm., showing elevations, sections and plan with notes and measurements]: Drawing 4 / [drawn by J.T.A.L.], August 22, 1949, NYDA.1986.004.02814
        - [Second floor :] cabinets at fireplace (L.R.) and plant shelf (D.R.) [showing interior elevations, plans, sections, and an isometric view, with notes and measurements]: Drawing 5/ [drawn by J.T.A.L.] 8/25/1949 to revised, 9/2/1949, NYDA.1986.004.02815
        - [Second floor :] color schedule with elevations [showing living rm., dining rm., library, kitchenette, master's bed room, passage, west bed rm., east bed rm., and hall interiors, with notes]: Drawing 6 / [drawn by J.T.A.L.], NYDA.1986.004.02816
        - [Second floor :] color schedule with elevations [showing living rm., dining rm., library, kitchenette, master's bed room, passage, west bed rm., east bed rm., and hall interiors, with notes]: Drawing 6 / [drawn by J.T.A.L.], September 8/1949, NYDA.1986.004.02817